<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>https://example.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://example.com/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientifiс programming languages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/scientifi%D1%81_programming_languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 08:53:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/scientifi%D1%81_programming_languages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-progress-of-computer-technology-has-determined-the-process-of-appearance-of-new-various-sign-systems-for-recording-algorithms---programming-languages-the-meaning-of-the-emergence-of-such-a-language---equipped-with-a-set-of-computational-formulas-of-additional-information-turns-this-set-into-an-algorithm-programming-language---a-formal-sign-system-designed-to-record-computer-programs-a-programming-language-defines-a-set-of-lexical-syntactic-and-semantic-rules-that-define-the-appearance-of-the-program-and-the-actions-that-the-executor-computer-will-perform-under-its-control&#34;&gt;The progress of computer technology has determined the process of appearance of new various sign systems for recording algorithms - programming languages. The meaning of the emergence of such a language - equipped with a set of computational formulas of additional information, turns this set into an algorithm. Programming language - a formal sign system designed to record computer programs. A programming language defines a set of lexical, syntactic and semantic rules that define the appearance of the program and the actions that the executor (computer) will perform under its control.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;since-the-creation-of-the-first-programmable-machines-mankind-has-come-up-with-more-than-eight-and-a-half-thousand-programming-languages-every-year-their-number-is-replenished-with-new-ones-some-languages-are-only-used-by-a-small-number-of-their-own-developers-others-are-known-to-millions-of-people-professional-programmers-sometimes-use-more-than-a-dozen-different-programming-languages-in-their-work&#34;&gt;Since the creation of the first programmable machines mankind has come up with more than eight and a half thousand programming languages. Every year their number is replenished with new ones. Some languages are only used by a small number of their own developers, others are known to millions of people. Professional programmers sometimes use more than a dozen different programming languages in their work.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;programming-languages&#34;&gt;Programming languages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-entire-set-of-programming-languages-can-be-divided-into-two-groups-low-level-languages-and-high-level-languages&#34;&gt;The entire set of programming languages can be divided into two groups: low-level languages and high-level languages.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-low-level-languages-are-assembly-languages-from-english-to-assemble-an-assembler-language-uses-symbolic-notation-of-commands-that-are-easy-to-understand-and-quick-to-remember-instead-of-binary-command-sequences-symbolic-designations-are-written-as-instructions-and-instead-of-binary-addresses-of-data-used-in-execution-of-instructions-symbolic-names-of-this-data-are-written-as-chosen-by-the-programmer-assembler-language-is-sometimes-called-mnemocode-or-autocode&#34;&gt;The low-level languages are assembly languages (from English to assemble). An assembler language uses symbolic notation of commands that are easy to understand and quick to remember. Instead of binary command sequences, symbolic designations are written as instructions and instead of binary addresses of data used in execution of instructions, symbolic names of this data are written as chosen by the programmer. Assembler language is sometimes called mnemocode or autocode.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-programmers-use-high-level-languages-to-write-programs-like-a-normal-human-language-such-a-language-has-its-own-alphabet---a-set-of-symbols-used-in-the-language-from-these-characters-are-compiled-what-are-called-keywords-of-the-language-each-of-the-keywords-performs-a-different-function-just-as-in-a-language-we-are-accustomed-to-words-composed-of-the-letters-of-the-alphabet-of-a-given-language-can-perform-the-functions-of-different-parts-of-speech-keywords-are-linked-together-into-sentences-according-to-certain-syntactic-rules-of-the-language-each-sentence-defines-a-certain-sequence-of-actions-to-be-performed-by-a-computer&#34;&gt;Most programmers use high-level languages to write programs. Like a normal human language, such a language has its own alphabet - a set of symbols used in the language. From these characters are compiled what are called keywords of the language. Each of the keywords performs a different function, just as in a language we are accustomed to, words composed of the letters of the alphabet of a given language can perform the functions of different parts of speech. Keywords are linked together into sentences according to certain syntactic rules of the language. Each sentence defines a certain sequence of actions to be performed by a computer.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-higher-level-language-acts-as-an-intermediary-between-humans-and-computers-allowing-humans-to-communicate-with-computers-in-a-more-human-readable-way-often-such-a-language-helps-to-choose-the-right-method-to-solve-a-problem&#34;&gt;A higher-level language acts as an intermediary between humans and computers, allowing humans to communicate with computers in a more human-readable way. Often such a language helps to choose the right method to solve a problem.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-writing-a-program-in-a-high-level-language-a-programmer-must-create-an-algorithm-for-solving-the-problem-that-is-a-step-by-step-plan-of-action-to-be-performed-to-solve-this-problem-this-is-why-languages-that-require-an-algorithm-to-be-compiled-in-advance-are-often-called-algorithmic-languages&#34;&gt;Before writing a program in a high-level language, a programmer must create an algorithm for solving the problem, that is, a step-by-step plan of action to be performed to solve this problem. This is why languages that require an algorithm to be compiled in advance are often called algorithmic languages.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;assembler&#34;&gt;Assembler&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-assembler-language-is-a-symbolic-representation-of-a-machine-language-it-makes-programming-easier-than-programming-in-machine-codes-the-programmer-does-not-have-to-use-the-real-addresses-of-the-memory-cells-with-the-data-in-them-involved-in-the-operation-and-the-calculated-results-as-well-as-the-addresses-of-the-commands-that-the-program-does-not-address-some-tasks-for-example-exchange-with-non-standard-data-processing-devices-of-complex-structures-cannot-be-solved-with-the-help-of-high-level-programming-languages&#34;&gt;The Assembler language is a symbolic representation of a machine language. It makes programming easier than programming in machine codes. The programmer does not have to use the real addresses of the memory cells with the data in them, involved in the operation, and the calculated results, as well as the addresses of the commands that the program does not address. Some tasks, for example, exchange with non-standard data processing devices of complex structures cannot be solved with the help of high-level programming languages.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-assembler-language-is-a-machine-language-and-the-programmer-realizing-any-task-in-high-level-languages-with-the-help-of-assembler-can-determine-whether-the-solution-to-this-problem-is-meaningful-in-terms-of-using-the-computer-the-ability-to-make-sense-of-the-assembler-language-makes-it-easier-to-find-errors-in-programs-because-some-languages-are-compilers&#34;&gt;The Assembler language is a machine language. And the programmer realizing any task in high-level languages, with the help of Assembler can determine whether the solution to this problem is meaningful, in terms of using the computer. The ability to make sense of the Assembler language makes it easier to find errors in programs because some languages are compilers.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;lisp&#34;&gt;Lisp&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lisp-the-second-oldest-programming-language-lisp-list-information-symbol-processing-was-developed-by-j-mccarthy-in-1962-to-handle-strings-of-symbols-rather-than-numbers-this-particular-purpose-of-lisp-opened-for-programmers-a-new-field-of-activity-known-today-as-artificial-intelligence-currently-lisp-is-successfully-used-in-expert-systems-analytical-computing-systems-etc&#34;&gt;Lisp The second oldest programming language, Lisp (List Information Symbol Processing), was developed by J. McCarthy in 1962 to handle strings of symbols rather than numbers. This particular purpose of Lisp opened for programmers a new field of activity known today as &amp;ldquo;artificial intelligence&amp;rdquo;. Currently, Lisp is successfully used in expert systems, analytical computing systems, etc.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-vast-area-of-possible-applications-of-lisp-caused-the-emergence-of-many-different-dialects-of-lisp-this-led-to-the-creation-of-the-common-lisp-committee-in-the-early-1980s-which-was-to-select-the-most-appropriate-lisp-dialect-and-propose-it-as-the-basic-one-this-dialect-chosen-by-the-committee-in-1985-was-called-common-lisp-it-has-since-been-adopted-by-us-universities-as-well-as-many-developers-of-artificial-intelligence-systems-as-the-basic-dialect-of-the-language-lisp&#34;&gt;The vast area of possible applications of Lisp caused the emergence of many different dialects of Lisp, this led to the creation of the Common LISP Committee in the early 1980s, which was to select the most appropriate Lisp dialect and propose it as the basic one. This dialect, chosen by the Committee in 1985, was called Common LISP. It has since been adopted by US universities, as well as many developers of artificial intelligence systems, as the basic dialect of the language Lisp.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initially-lisp-was-conceived-as-a-theoretical-tool-for-recursive-constructions-but-today-it-has-become-a-powerful-tool-that-provides-the-programmer-with-a-variety-of-support-allowing-him-to-quickly-build-prototypes-of-very-very-serious-systems-professor-j-samman-of-the-massachusetts-institute-of-technology-noted-that-the-mathematical-clarity-and-ultimate-clarity-of-lisp-is-not-all-the-main-thing-is-that-lisp-allows-to-formulate-and-memorize-idioms-so-characteristic-of-artificial-intelligence-projects&#34;&gt;Initially Lisp was conceived as a theoretical tool for recursive constructions, but today it has become a powerful tool that provides the programmer with a variety of support, allowing him to quickly build prototypes of very, very serious systems. Professor J. Samman of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology noted that the mathematical clarity and ultimate clarity of Lisp is not all. The main thing is that Lisp allows to formulate and memorize &amp;ldquo;idioms&amp;rdquo; so characteristic of artificial intelligence projects.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic&#34;&gt;Basic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-mid-60s-1963-dartmouth-college-usa-created-the-basic-language-basic-from-beginners-allpurpose-instructional-code-over-time-as-other-dialects-began-to-appear-this-original-dialect-became-known-as-dartmouth-basic-the-language-was-based-partly-on-fortran-ii-and-partly-on-algol-60-with-additions-making-it-suitable-for-time-sharing-and-later-text-processing-and-matrix-arithmetic-basics-was-originally-implemented-on-the-ge-265-mainframe-with-support-for-multiple-terminals-contrary-to-popular-belief-it-was-a-compiled-language-at-its-inception-basic-was-designed-so-that-students-could-write-programs-using-time-sharing-terminals-it-was-created-as-a-solution-to-problems-with-the-complexity-of-older-languages-it-was-intended-for-more-simple-users-not-so-much-interested-in-the-speed-of-programs-but-simply-in-being-able-to-use-the-computer-to-do-their-jobs&#34;&gt;In the mid 60&amp;rsquo;s (1963) Dartmouth College (USA) created the BASIC language (BASIC from Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Allpurpose Instructional Code). Over time, as other dialects began to appear, this &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; dialect became known as Dartmouth BASIC. The language was based partly on Fortran II and partly on Algol-60, with additions making it suitable for time-sharing and, later, text processing and matrix arithmetic. Basics was originally implemented on the GE-265 mainframe with support for multiple terminals. Contrary to popular belief, it was a compiled language at its inception. Basic was designed so that students could write programs using time-sharing terminals. It was created as a solution to problems with the complexity of older languages. It was intended for more &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; users, not so much interested in the speed of programs, but simply in being able to use the computer to do their jobs.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;with-the-advent-of-microsofts-quickbasic-translator-developers-were-able-to-build-applications-in-basic-from-separately-compiled-modules-some-of-which-could-be-written-in-other-languages-now-as-in-the-case-of-other-leading-programming-languages-the-developer-has-a-choice-of-several-industrial-subroutine-libraries-which-contain-ready-made-solutions-for-common-programming-tasks&#34;&gt;With the advent of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s QuickBasic translator, developers were able to build applications in Basic from separately compiled modules, some of which could be written in other languages. Now, as in the case of other leading programming languages, the developer has a choice of several industrial subroutine libraries, which contain ready-made solutions for common programming tasks.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;c&#34;&gt;C&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-is-a-general-purpose-programming-language-well-known-for-its-efficiency-cost-effectiveness-and-portability-in-c-you-can-create-programs-that-do-anything-you-want-another-advantage-of-c-is-that-it-allows-you-to-use-all-the-features-of-your-computer&#34;&gt;It is a general-purpose programming language well known for its efficiency, cost-effectiveness, and portability. In C you can create programs that do anything you want. Another advantage of C is that it allows you to use all the features of your computer.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c-language-features-provides-a-complete-set-of-structural-programming-statements-supports-pointers-to-variables-and-functions-contains-a-preprocessor-that-processes-text-files-before-compilation-allows-you-to-make-a-variety-of-decisions-in-specific-situations&#34;&gt;C language features: provides a complete set of structural programming statements; supports pointers to variables and functions; contains a preprocessor that processes text files before compilation; allows you to make a variety of decisions in specific situations.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;c-1&#34;&gt;C++&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-name-c-was-invented-by-rick-massitti-in-1983-it-indicates-the-evolutionary-nature-of-the-move-to-it-from-c--is-an-incremental-operation-in-c-the-slightly-shorter-name-c-is-a-syntax-error-and-has-already-been-used-as-the-name-of-an-entirely-different-language&#34;&gt;The name C++ was invented by Rick Massitti in 1983. It indicates the evolutionary nature of the move to it from C. &amp;ldquo;++&amp;rdquo; is an incremental operation in C. The slightly shorter name C++ is a syntax error and has already been used as the name of an entirely different language.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c-is-a-superset-of-the-c-programming-language-in-addition-to-the-features-that-c-provides-c-provides-a-flexible-and-efficient-means-of-defining-new-types-using-definitions-of-new-types-that-correspond-exactly-to-the-concepts-of-the-application-the-programmer-can-divide-the-program-being-developed-into-easily-controllable-parts-this-method-of-constructing-programs-is-often-called-data-abstraction-type-information-is-contained-in-some-user-defined-type-objects&#34;&gt;C++ is a superset of the C programming language. In addition to the features that C provides, C++ provides a flexible and efficient means of defining new types. Using definitions of new types that correspond exactly to the concepts of the application, the programmer can divide the program being developed into easily controllable parts. This method of constructing programs is often called data abstraction. Type information is contained in some user-defined type objects.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;such-objects-are-easy-and-reliable-to-use-in-situations-where-their-type-cannot-be-set-at-compile-time-c-was-chosen-as-the-base-language-for-c-because-it-is-versatile-concise-and-relatively-low-level-meets-most-system-programming-tasks-goes-everywhere-and-on-everything-and-is-suitable-in-the-unix-programming-environment&#34;&gt;Such objects are easy and reliable to use in situations where their type cannot be set at compile time. C was chosen as the base language for C++ because it is: versatile, concise and relatively low-level, meets most system programming tasks, goes everywhere and on everything, and is suitable in the UNIX programming environment.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pascal&#34;&gt;Pascal&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;it-is-a-high-level-general-purpose-programming-language-one-of-the-most-famous-programming-languages-it-is-widely-used-in-industrial-programming-teaching-programming-in-higher-education-and-is-the-basis-for-a-large-number-of-other-languages-it-was-created-by-niklaus-wirth-in-19689-published-in-1970-after-his-participation-in-the-algol-68-standard-development-committee-pascal-was-created-as-a-language-for-teaching-procedural-programming-the-language-was-named-after-blaise-pascal-the-prominent-17th-century-french-mathematician-physicist-literary-writer-and-philosopher-inventor-of-the-worlds-first-arithmetic-machine-the-pascal-compiler-was-written-in-pascal-itself-using-the-unwinding-method-where-the-core-of-the-language-is-created-with-a-gradual-build-up-of-new-features&#34;&gt;It is a high-level general-purpose programming language. One of the most famous programming languages, it is widely used in industrial programming, teaching programming in higher education, and is the basis for a large number of other languages. It was created by Niklaus Wirth in 1968/9 (published in 1970), after his participation in the Algol-68 standard development committee. Pascal was created as a language for teaching procedural programming. The language was named after Blaise Pascal, the prominent 17th century French mathematician, physicist, literary writer, and philosopher, inventor of the world&amp;rsquo;s first arithmetic machine. The Pascal compiler was written in Pascal itself, using the &amp;ldquo;unwinding method&amp;rdquo;, where the core of the language is created, with a gradual build-up of new features.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-features-of-the-language-are-strict-typing-and-the-presence-of-structural-procedural-programming-pascal-minimizes-possible-syntactic-ambiguities-and-the-author-tried-to-make-the-syntax-itself-intuitively-understandable-even-when-you-first-learn-the-language&#34;&gt;The features of the language are strict typing and the presence of structural (procedural) programming. Pascal minimizes possible syntactic ambiguities and the author tried to make the syntax itself intuitively understandable even when you first learn the language.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;java&#34;&gt;Java&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;java-is-an-object-oriented-programming-language-developed-by-sunmicrosystems-java-applications-are-usually-compiled-into-special-byte-code-so-they-can-run-on-any-java-virtual-machine-jvm-regardless-of-the-computer-architecture-the-official-release-date-was-may-23-1995-the-language-was-originally-called-oak-oak-and-was-developed-by-james-gosling-for-programming-consumer-electronic-devices-later-it-was-renamed-java-and-was-used-for-writing-client-applications-and-server-software-named-after-the-coffee-brand-java-so-the-official-emblem-of-the-language-depicts-a-cup-with-steaming-coffee&#34;&gt;Java is an object-oriented programming language developed by SunMicrosystems. Java applications are usually compiled into special byte-code, so they can run on any Java Virtual Machine (JVM) regardless of the computer architecture. The official release date was May 23, 1995. The language was originally called Oak (&amp;ldquo;oak&amp;rdquo;) and was developed by James Gosling for programming consumer electronic devices. Later it was renamed Java and was used for writing client applications and server software. Named after the coffee brand Java, so the official emblem of the language depicts a cup with steaming coffee.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-advantage-of-program-execution-is-in-complete-independence-of-bytecode-from-operating-system-and-equipment-allows-to-execute-java-applications-on-any-device-for-which-there-is-a-corresponding-virtual-machine-another-important-feature-of-java-technology-is-flexible-security-system-due-to-the-fact-that-program-execution-is-fully-controlled-by-virtual-machine-any-operation-that-exceeds-the-programs-set-authority-eg-attempting-unauthorized-access-to-data-or-connecting-to-another-computer-will-cause-an-immediate-interruption&#34;&gt;The advantage of program execution is in complete independence of bytecode from operating system and equipment allows to execute Java applications on any device for which there is a corresponding virtual machine. Another important feature of Java technology is flexible security system due to the fact that program execution is fully controlled by virtual machine. Any operation that exceeds the program&amp;rsquo;s set authority (e.g. attempting unauthorized access to data or connecting to another computer) will cause an immediate interruption.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-of-the-disadvantages-of-the-virtual-machine-concept-is-that-the-execution-of-byte-code-by-a-virtual-machine-can-degrade-the-performance-of-programs-and-algorithms-implemented-in-the-java-language-this-was-true-for-the-first-versions-of-the-java-virtual-machine-but-lately-it-has-become-almost-irrelevant-a-number-of-improvements-contributed-to-this-the-use-of-bytecode-to-machine-code-translation-technology-jit-technology-with-the-ability-to-save-class-versions-in-machine-code-wide-use-of-platform-oriented-native-code-in-standard-libraries-hardware-that-provides-accelerated-bytecode-processing-for-example-jazelle-technology-supported-by-some-arm-processors&#34;&gt;One of the disadvantages of the virtual machine concept is that the execution of byte code by a virtual machine can degrade the performance of programs and algorithms implemented in the Java language. This was true for the first versions of the Java Virtual Machine, but lately it has become almost irrelevant. A number of improvements contributed to this: the use of bytecode-to-machine-code translation technology (JIT-technology) with the ability to save class versions in machine code, wide use of platform-oriented (native-code) in standard libraries, hardware that provides accelerated bytecode processing (for example, Jazelle technology supported by some ARM processors).&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ideas-behind-the-concept-and-the-various-implementations-of-the-java-virtual-machine-environment-have-inspired-many-enthusiasts-to-expand-the-list-of-languages-that-could-be-used-to-create-programs-that-run-on-the-virtual-machinethese-ideas-also-found-expression-in-the-specification-of-the-common-language-infrastructure-cli-which-is-the-basis-of-the-net-platform-by-microsoft&#34;&gt;The ideas behind the concept and the various implementations of the Java virtual machine environment have inspired many enthusiasts to expand the list of languages that could be used to create programs that run on the virtual machine.These ideas also found expression in the specification of the common language infrastructure CLI, which is the basis of the .NET platform by Microsoft.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-invention-of-higher-level-programming-languages-as-well-as-their-constant-improvement-and-development-allowed-man-not-only-to-communicate-with-and-understand-the-machine-but-to-use-computers-for-the-most-complex-calculations-in-the-fields-of-aircraft-rocket-science-medicine-and-even-economics&#34;&gt;The invention of higher-level programming languages, as well as their constant improvement and development, allowed man not only to communicate with and understand the machine, but to use computers for the most complex calculations in the fields of aircraft, rocket science, medicine and even economics.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;today-any-medium-or-large-enterprise-has-a-group-of-programmers-with-knowledge-of-programming-in-different-languages-who-edit-change-and-modify-the-programs-used-by-the-employees-of-the-enterprise-this-shows-that-people-with-knowledge-and-experience-with-various-programming-languages-are-in-demand-in-the-labor-market&#34;&gt;Today, any medium or large enterprise has a group of programmers with knowledge of programming in different languages, who edit, change and modify the programs used by the employees of the enterprise. This shows that people with knowledge and experience with various programming languages are in demand in the labor market.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;that-is-i-have-proven-that-with-the-improvement-of-old-programming-languages-and-the-creation-of-new-ones-it-has-become-easier-for-people-to-work-and-programming-has-become-less-complicated&#34;&gt;That is, I have proven that with the improvement of old programming languages and the creation of new ones, it has become easier for people to work and programming has become less complicated.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-this-project-i-looked-at-the-most-common-programming-languages-such-as-fortran-pascal-basic-which-are-used-for-scientific-calculations-to-teach-programming-to-novice-programmers&#34;&gt;In this project I looked at the most common programming languages such as: Fortran, Pascal, Basic, which are used for scientific calculations, to teach programming to novice programmers.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;at-the-moment-i-am-already-learning-programming-in-python-and-i-am-thinking-about-tying-my-life-to-the-profession-of-a-programmer&#34;&gt;At the moment I am already learning programming in Python and I am thinking about tying my life to the profession of a programmer.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;despite-the-fact-that-the-current-level-of-development-of-programming-languages-is-quite-high-the-tendency-of-their-development-as-well-as-the-development-of-information-technology-in-general-is-such-that-it-can-be-assumed-that-in-the-near-future-human-knowledge-in-this-area-will-help-to-produce-languages-that-can-receive-process-and-transmit-information-in-the-form-of-thought-word-sound-or-gesture&#34;&gt;Despite the fact that the current level of development of programming languages is quite high, the tendency of their development, as well as the development of information technology in general, is such that it can be assumed that in the near future, human knowledge in this area will help to produce languages that can receive, process and transmit information in the form of thought, word, sound or gesture.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/mylastweek/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 08:52:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/mylastweek/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-last-week&#34;&gt;My last week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-week-was-not-as-busy-as-the-previous-ones-this-week-we-had-the-last-physical-education-and-english-classes-i-have-done-a-lot-of-laboratory-work-shot-a-lot-of-video-reports-ive-watched-a-lot-of-videos-on-youtube-thats-how-my-week-went&#34;&gt;This week was not as busy as the previous ones. This week we had the last physical education and English classes. I have done a lot of laboratory work, shot a lot of video reports. I&amp;rsquo;ve watched a lot of videos on youtube. That&amp;rsquo;s how my week went.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;result-of-the-week&#34;&gt;Result of the week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-think-this-week-has-been-less-productive-than-others-this-week-i-rested-more-watched-videos-on-the-internet-and-slept&#34;&gt;I think this week has been less productive than others. This week I rested more, watched videos on the internet and slept.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual project &#34;Personal site of a researcher&#34;</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-the-subject-operating-systems-i-had-to-do-a-project---to-create-a-personal-website-the-project-consisted-of-6-stages-each-of-which-was-allocated-a-week-during-the-stages-i-had-to-write-and-create-posts-on-various-topics-add-information-about-myself-and-so-on&#34;&gt;In the subject &amp;ldquo;Operating Systems&amp;rdquo; I had to do a project - to create a personal website. The project consisted of 6 stages, each of which was allocated a week. During the stages I had to write and create posts on various topics, add information about myself, and so on.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;stages-of-the-project&#34;&gt;Stages of the project:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-posting-on-github-pages-the-blanks-for-the-personal-site&#34;&gt;1) Posting on Github pages the blanks for the personal site.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-add-data-about-yourself-to-the-site-make-a-post-on-the-last-week-and-make-a-post-on-a-topic-of-choice&#34;&gt;2) Add data about yourself to the site. Make a post on the last week and make a post on a topic of choice.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-add-an-accomplishments-to-the-site-make-a-post-on-the-last-week-and-make-a-post-on-a-topic-of-choice&#34;&gt;3) Add an accomplishments to the site. Make a post on the last week and make a post on a topic of choice.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-add-links-to-scholarly-and-bibliometric-resources-to-the-site-make-a-post-on-the-last-week-and-make-a-post-on-a-topic-of-choice&#34;&gt;4) Add links to scholarly and bibliometric resources to the site. Make a post on the last week and make a post on a topic of choice.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-add-all-other-elements-to-the-site-make-a-post-on-the-last-week-and-make-a-post-on-a-topic-of-choice&#34;&gt;5) Add all other elements to the site. Make a post on the last week and make a post on a topic of choice.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-post-a-bilingual-site-on-github-make-a-post-on-the-last-week-and-make-a-post-on-a-topic-of-choice-bilingually&#34;&gt;6) Post a bilingual site on Github. Make a post on the last week and make a post on a topic of choice (bilingually).&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating presentations</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/creating_presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 07:26:55 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/creating_presentations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-of-us-have-at-least-once-got-to-a-performance-with-an-impossibly-boring-presentation-the-slides-were-overloaded-with-information-the-speech-was-monotonous-there-was-snuffling-in-the-hall-the-content-of-such-speeches-disappears-from-memory-a-minute-after-the-start&#34;&gt;All of us have at least once got to a performance with an impossibly boring presentation. The slides were overloaded with information, the speech was monotonous, there was snuffling in the hall. The content of such speeches disappears from memory a minute after the start.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-not-all-presentations-are-like-that-some-do-not-get-out-of-my-head-for-weeks-and-the-words-from-them-inspire-me-to-act-a-good-presentation-is-understandable-even-to-a-child-beautifully-designed-and-combined-with-a-strong-idea-can-change-the-world&#34;&gt;But not all presentations are like that. Some do not get out of my head for weeks, and the words from them inspire me to act. A good presentation is understandable even to a child, beautifully designed, and combined with a strong idea can change the world.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-make-a-beautiful-and-interesting-presentation-easier-than-it-looks-you-dont-need-to-be-a-designer-or-steve-jobs-to-do-this-its-enough-to-follow-the-simple-rules-and-tricks-from-this-article-with-them-you-will-be-able-to-inspire-convey-ideas-and-convince-people-through-presentations-and-if-time-is-tight-use-readymade-canva-templates---much-of-what-we-are-talking-about-below-is-already-there&#34;&gt;How to make a beautiful and interesting presentation? Easier than it looks. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be a designer or Steve Jobs to do this, it&amp;rsquo;s enough to follow the simple rules and tricks from this article. With them, you will be able to inspire, convey ideas and convince people through presentations. And if time is tight, use ready—made Canva templates - much of what we are talking about below is already there.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-prepare-for-the-presentation&#34;&gt;How to prepare for the presentation?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-you-sit-down-at-the-editor-ask-yourself-a-few-questions-who-is-your-audience-what-is-the-main-idea-of-the-presentation-how-will-you-prove-it-what-should-people-understand-and-do-after-your-words-the-better-you-prepare-before-the-speech-the-more-accurate-your-message-will-be-even-if-the-presentation-is-watched-online-studying-the-recipients-and-working-on-the-structure-will-not-be-in-vain&#34;&gt;Before you sit down at the editor, ask yourself a few questions: Who is your audience? What is the main idea of the presentation? How will you prove it? What should people understand and do after your words? The better you prepare before the speech, the more accurate your message will be. Even if the presentation is watched online, studying the recipients and working on the structure will not be in vain.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-main-idea&#34;&gt;The main idea&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-presentations-always-have-a-main-idea-that-runs-through-the-whole-performance-like-a-red-thread-it-can-be-a-call-a-push-to-a-decision-or-a-plan-without-a-clear-idea-presentations-get-messy-and-confusing-and-it-can-be-difficult-for-listeners-to-understand-what-the-author-wanted-to-say&#34;&gt;Good presentations always have a main idea that runs through the whole performance like a red thread. It can be a call, a push to a decision, or a plan. Without a clear idea, presentations get messy and confusing, and it can be difficult for listeners to understand what the author wanted to say.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-main-idea-should-be-short-simple-and-memorable-as-a-motto-or-slogan&#34;&gt;The main idea should be short, simple and memorable. As a motto or slogan.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dream-is-the-most-important-part-of-any-presentation-after-you-find-and-isolate-the-central-idea-you-will-understand-how-to-create-a-presentation-around-it-check-each-slide-with-a-question-why-is-it-important-for-the-idea-so-everything-that-does-not-help-to-reveal-the-idea-will-simply-remain-behind-the-scenes&#34;&gt;The dream is the most important part of any presentation After you find and isolate the central idea, you will understand how to create a presentation around it. Check each slide with a question: &amp;ldquo;Why is it important for the idea?&amp;rdquo; So everything that does not help to reveal the idea will simply remain behind the scenes.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sometimes-even-strong-ideas-get-lost-in-presentations-with-a-chaotic-structure-to-prevent-this-from-happening-sort-everything-out-in-advance-here-are-a-few-ways-by-which-you-can-interestingly-convey-the-main-idea-start-with-a-little-provocation-bang-point-to-a-problem-gap-provide-evidence-and-propose-a-solution-main-thoughts-tell-a-story-and-call-for-action-explain-the-complex-according-to-the-principle-of-explain-like-im-5-give-brief-conclusions-and-motivation-to-work-with-them-wrap-up-it-is-not-necessary-to-take-all-six-methods-into-the-presentation-any-three-will-be-enough-for-a-good-presentation&#34;&gt;Sometimes even strong ideas get lost in presentations with a chaotic structure. To prevent this from happening, sort everything out in advance. Here are a few ways by which you can interestingly convey the main idea: Start with a little provocation (bang); Point to a problem (gap); Provide evidence and propose a solution (main thoughts); Tell a story and call for action; Explain the complex according to the principle of &amp;ldquo;Explain like I&amp;rsquo;m 5&amp;rdquo;; Give brief conclusions and motivation to work with them (wrap up). It is not necessary to take all six methods into the presentation, any three will be enough for a good presentation.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-make-a-cool-presentation&#34;&gt;How to make a cool presentation?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;now-that-the-audience-is-in-complete-order-with-ideas-and-content-you-can-finally-take-up-the-slides-but-first-a-few-hints&#34;&gt;Now that the audience is in complete order with ideas and content, you can finally take up the slides! But first, a few hints.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dont-forget-the-rule-one-slide--one-thought-choose-sans-serif-fonts-write-large-use-bright-talking-photos-choose-cool-templates&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget the rule &amp;ldquo;one slide — one thought&amp;rdquo;; Choose sans-serif fonts; Write large; Use bright talking photos; Choose cool templates.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-tell-a-presentation&#34;&gt;How to tell a presentation?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-you-have-recognized-the-audience-formulated-the-message-and-told-it-by-simple-means-then-your-presentation-is-already-cooler-than-anything-that-can-be-found-on-the-internet-you-can-try-to-go-further-and-figure-out-how-to-make-the-presentation-even-better-due-to-the-steep-pitch&#34;&gt;If you have recognized the audience, formulated the message and told it by simple means, then your presentation is already cooler than anything that can be found on the Internet. You can try to go further and figure out how to make the presentation even better due to the steep pitch.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rehearse-your-speech-speak-slowly-try-to-keep-within-10-minutes-use-slides-as-a-background-learn-from-the-best&#34;&gt;Rehearse your speech; Speak slowly; Try to keep within 10 minutes; Use slides as a background; Learn from the best.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 07:13:08 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/week3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-last-week&#34;&gt;My last week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-week-turned-out-to-be-diverse-i-did-a-lot-of-things-for-my-studies-but-i-also-did-not-forget-about-recreation-and-entertainment-my-friend-had-a-birthday-and-we-went-on-a-horror-quest-we-got-unforgettable-emotions-then-we-ate-pizza-and-walked-in-gorky-park-until-nightfall&#34;&gt;This week turned out to be diverse. I did a lot of things for my studies, but I also did not forget about recreation and entertainment. My friend had a birthday and we went on a horror quest. We got unforgettable emotions. Then we ate pizza and walked in Gorky Park until nightfall.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;result-of-the-week&#34;&gt;Result of the week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-think-this-week-has-been-productive-i-was-able-to-find-a-balance-between-studying-and-relaxing-so-the-week-turned-out-great&#34;&gt;I think this week has been productive. I was able to find a balance between studying and relaxing, so the week turned out great.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 18:55:24 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;markdown-is-a-text-markup-language-created-by-writer-and-blogger-john-gruber-it-is-designed-to-create-beautifully-designed-texts-in-ordinary-txt-format-files-you-dont-need-bulky-processors-like-word-or-pages-to-create-documents-with-bold-or-italics-citations-links-and-even-tables-it-is-enough-to-remember-the-simple-rules-of-markdown-and-you-can-write-even-in-a-notebook-although-specialized-markdown-editors-are-of-course-much-more-convenient&#34;&gt;Markdown is a text markup language created by writer and blogger John Gruber. It is designed to create beautifully designed texts in ordinary TXT format files. You don&amp;rsquo;t need bulky processors like Word or Pages to create documents with bold or italics, citations, links, and even tables. It is enough to remember the simple rules of Markdown, and you can write even in a &amp;ldquo;Notebook&amp;rdquo;. Although specialized Markdown editors are, of course, much more convenient.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;where-can-i-use-markdown&#34;&gt;Where can I use Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-the-markdown-editor-with-a-file-panel-for-example-atom-or-ia-writer-is-quite-a-worthy-alternative-to-evernote-and-onenote-we-have-already-written-why-markdown-is-good-for-organizing-your-database-of-notes&#34;&gt;Notes: The Markdown editor with a file panel (for example, Atom or iA Writer) is quite a worthy alternative to Evernote and OneNote. We have already written why Markdown is good for organizing your database of notes.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;drafts-for-the-blog-this-markup-language-is-compatible-with-a-bunch-of-online-editors-and-blog-platforms-you-can-write-a-draft-for-your-blog-in-markdown-and-then-publish-it-in-seconds--all-links-titles-and-formatting-will-look-as-you-intended-this-is-not-for-you-to-copy-from-word&#34;&gt;Drafts for the blog: This markup language is compatible with a bunch of online editors and blog platforms. You can write a draft for your blog in Markdown, and then publish it in seconds — all links, titles and formatting will look as you intended. This is not for you to copy from Word.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;task-lists-it-is-very-easy-to-create-shopping-lists-to-do-lists-and-work-assignments-in-markdown-editors-some-geeks-use-a-plain-text-file-todotxt-as-an-alternative-to-the-fashionable-wunderlist-and-todoist-how-to-do-this-you-can-find-out-on-the-website-todotxt-&#34;&gt;Task lists: It is very easy to create shopping lists, to-do lists, and work assignments in Markdown editors. Some geeks use a plain text file todo.txt as an alternative to the fashionable Wunderlist and Todoist. How to do this, you can find out on the website Todo.txt .&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;messengers-even-some-messengers-support-markdown-for-example-in-telegram-you-can-use-it-to-apply-bold-or-italic-highlighting&#34;&gt;Messengers: Even some messengers support Markdown. For example, in Telegram, you can use it to apply bold or italic highlighting.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;advantages-of-markdown&#34;&gt;Advantages of Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;versatility-documents-written-using-markdown-syntax-are-plain-text-txt-files-they-can-be-opened-on-any-platform-and-in-any-editor-in-this-way-they-differ-favorably-from-files-created-in-word-processors-have-you-tried-opening-a-document-from-apple-pages-in-word&#34;&gt;Versatility: Documents written using Markdown syntax are plain text TXT files. They can be opened on any platform and in any editor. In this way they differ favorably from files created in word processors. Have you tried opening a document from Apple Pages in Word?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;simplicity-markdown-is-so-simple-that-even-those-who-have-not-heard-about-all-your-latex-and-html-before-will-be-able-to-master-it-in-10-minutes-grids-for-subheadings-asterisks-for-highlighting-dashes-for-lists-it-couldnt-be-simpler&#34;&gt;Simplicity: Markdown is so simple that even those who have not heard about all your Latex and HTML before will be able to master it in 10 minutes. Grids for subheadings, asterisks for highlighting, dashes for lists. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t be simpler.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-large-selection-of-editing-tools-for-working-with-markdown-documents-is-very-very-much-there-are-online-mobile-and-desktop-tools-there-is-a-monstrous-atom-beautiful-and-minimalistic-ghostwriter-and-ia-writer-vim-for-geeks-and-ulysses-for-professional-writers-i-dont-want-to-choose&#34;&gt;A large selection: of Editing tools for working with Markdown documents is very, very much. There are online, mobile, and desktop tools. There is a monstrous Atom, beautiful and minimalistic ghostwriter and iA Writer, Vim for geeks and Ulysses for professional writers. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to choose.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;convertibility-markdown-documents-can-be-easily-exported-to-any-formats-pdf-doc-odt-at-the-same-time-their-formatting-remains-unchanged&#34;&gt;Convertibility: Markdown documents can be easily exported to any formats: PDF, DOC, ODT. At the same time, their formatting remains unchanged.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;disadvantages-of-markdown&#34;&gt;Disadvantages of Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;limited-formatting-since-markdown-documents-are-just-text-files-you-cant-use-beautiful-fonts-in-them-after-all-it-is-more-of-a-tool-for-writing-drafts-than-for-full-fledged-layout&#34;&gt;Limited formatting: Since Markdown documents are just text files, you can&amp;rsquo;t use beautiful fonts in them. After all, it is more of a tool for writing drafts than for full-fledged layout.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strict-rules-in-markdown-the-text-is-formatted-using-service-characters-one-extra-character--or--and-the-formatting-will-change-so-when-typing-texts-in-markdown-you-will-have-to-be-careful&#34;&gt;Strict rules: In Markdown, the text is formatted using service characters. One extra character * or #, and the formatting will change. So when typing texts in Markdown, you will have to be careful.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;applications-for-markdown&#34;&gt;Applications for Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-can-easily-choose-your-favorite-text-editor-from-our-selection-atom-is-considered-one-of-the-best-for-markdown--it-is-good-for-its-incredible-flexibility-and-versatility-it-works-on-windows-macos-and-linux-and-has-a-huge-number-of-themes-and-extensions-it-is-very-easy-to-assemble-a-dream-editor-from-it-macos-users-should-pay-attention-to-the-beautiful-and-convenient-editors-ia-writer-write-and-byword&#34;&gt;You can easily choose your favorite text editor from our selection. Atom is considered one of the best for Markdown — it is good for its incredible flexibility and versatility. It works on Windows, macOS and Linux and has a huge number of themes and extensions. It is very easy to assemble a dream editor from it. MacOS users should pay attention to the beautiful and convenient editors iA Writer, Write and Byword.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last_week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 18:53:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last_week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-last-week&#34;&gt;My last week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-week-i-did-all-the-things-i-planned-to-do-i-did-all-the-lab-work-solved-the-tests-did-my-homework-in-english-in-addition-i-did-not-forget-about-the-rest-my-friends-and-i-went-to-the-trampoline-park&#34;&gt;This week I did all the things I planned to do. I did all the lab work, solved the tests, did my homework in English. In addition, I did not forget about the rest. My friends and I went to the trampoline park.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;result-of-the-week&#34;&gt;Result of the week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-think-this-week-has-been-productive-i-completed-all-the-tasks-and-had-time-to-rest-relax-and-sleep-a-lot-i-hope-next-week-will-be-no-less-productive&#34;&gt;I think this week has been productive. I completed all the tasks and had time to rest, relax and sleep a lot. I hope next week will be no less productive.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/tema2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 07:29:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/tema2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-speed-and-quality-of-product-assembly-are-the-main-competitive-advantages-in-software-development-therefore-a-new-concept-of-cicd--continuous-integration-and-continuous-delivery--continuous-integration-and-continuous-delivery---began-to-replace-archaic-programming-models-such-as-imperative-structural-or-modular-it-helps-to-minimize-errors-increase-the-pace-of-assembly-and-the-quality-of-the-product-being-developed&#34;&gt;The speed and quality of product assembly are the main competitive advantages in software development. Therefore, a new concept of CI/CD — Continuous integration and Continuous delivery – continuous integration and continuous delivery - began to replace archaic programming models, such as imperative, structural or modular. It helps to minimize errors, increase the pace of assembly and the quality of the product being developed.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-cicd&#34;&gt;What is CI/CD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cicd-is-one-of-the-devops-practices-that-implies-continuous-integration-and-delivery-this-set-of-principles-is-designed-to-improve-the-convenience-frequency-and-reliability-of-deploying-software-or-product-changes-cicd-refers-to-agile-practices-and-allows-developers-to-pay-attention-to-the-implementation-of-business-requirements-code-quality-and-product-security-cicd-goals-providing-a-consistent-and-automated-way-to-assemble-package-and-test-products-or-applicationsautomation-of-deployment-in-different-environments-minimizing-errors-and-problems&#34;&gt;CI/CD is one of the DevOps practices that implies continuous integration and delivery. This set of principles is designed to improve the convenience, frequency, and reliability of deploying software or product changes. CI/CD refers to agile practices and allows developers to pay attention to the implementation of business requirements, code quality and product security. CI/CD Goals: providing a consistent and automated way to assemble, package, and test products or applications;automation of deployment in different environments; minimizing errors and problems.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cicd-principles&#34;&gt;CI/CD Principles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;there-are-four-guiding-principles-for-cicd&#34;&gt;There are four guiding principles for CI/CD.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1division-of-responsibility-each-of-the-participants-in-the-process-shares-responsibility-for-certain-stages-of-the-product-life-cycle-business-logistics-is-being-designed-end-to-end-functions-are-being-implemented-acceptance-tests-are-being-conducted-and-code-logistics-is-being-organized&#34;&gt;1)Division of responsibility. Each of the participants in the process shares responsibility for certain stages of the product life cycle. Business logistics is being designed, end-to-end functions are being implemented, acceptance tests are being conducted and code logistics is being organized.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2risk-reduction-each-team-involved-in-product-development-strives-to-reduce-risks--the-correctness-of-business-logistics-is-monitored-user-experience-is-checked-data-storage-and-processing-are-improved-and-so-on&#34;&gt;2)Risk reduction. Each team involved in product development strives to reduce risks — the correctness of business logistics is monitored, user experience is checked, data storage and processing are improved, and so on.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3shortening-the-feedback-loop-the-developer-and-the-client-should-strive-to-increase-the-speed-of-making-changes-and-approving-edits-code-assembly-and-testing-can-be-automated-and-for-situations-where-human-participation-is-required-it-is-possible-to-minimize-the-number-of-information-intermediaries&#34;&gt;3)Shortening the feedback loop. The developer and the client should strive to increase the speed of making changes and approving edits. Code assembly and testing can be automated. And for situations where human participation is required, it is possible to minimize the number of information intermediaries.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4implementation-of-the-environment-developers-should-have-a-common-workspace-with-the-main-and-auxiliary-branches-for-version-control-and-quality-acceptability-fault-tolerance-etc&#34;&gt;4)Implementation of the environment. Developers should have a common workspace with the main and auxiliary branches for version control and quality, acceptability, fault tolerance, etc.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cicd-stages&#34;&gt;CI/CD Stages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cicd-methodology-involves-dividing-the-development-process-into-seven-stages&#34;&gt;The CI/CD methodology involves dividing the development process into seven stages.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1writing-code-developers-write-the-code-of-their-module-and-conduct-manual-testing-after-that-the-result-of-the-work-is-connected-in-the-main-branch-with-the-current-version-of-the-project-after-all-the-module-codes-are-published-in-the-main-branch-the-second-stage-begins&#34;&gt;1)Writing code. Developers write the code of their module and conduct manual testing. After that, the result of the work is connected in the main branch with the current version of the project. After all the module codes are published in the main branch, the second stage begins.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2assembling-the-selected-version-control-system-initiates-the-automatic-build-and-subsequent-testing-of-the-project-triggers-for-activating-the-build-can-be-configured-independently-jenkins-or-another-tool-is-used-to-automate-the-assembly&#34;&gt;2)Assembling. The selected version control system initiates the automatic build and subsequent testing of the project. Triggers for activating the build can be configured independently. Jenkins or another tool is used to automate the assembly.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3manual-testing-after-the-ci-system-checks-the-operability-of-the-test-version-the-code-is-transmitted-for-manual-investigation&#34;&gt;3)Manual testing. After the CI system checks the operability of the test version, the code is transmitted for manual investigation.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4release-after-manual-testing-corrections-are-made-to-the-assembly-next-comes-the-release-of-the-code-version-for-customers&#34;&gt;4)Release. After manual testing, corrections are made to the assembly. Next comes the release of the code version for customers.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5deployment-at-this-stage-the-current-working-version-of-the-code-is-hosted-on-the-developers-production-servers-the-client-can-interact-with-the-program-and-learn-its-functions&#34;&gt;5)Deployment. At this stage, the current (working) version of the code is hosted on the developer&amp;rsquo;s production servers. The client can interact with the program and learn its functions.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6support-and-monitoring-the-product-begins-to-be-used-by-end-users-at-the-same-time-the-developers-continue-to-support-it-and-analyze-the-user-experience&#34;&gt;6)Support and monitoring. The product begins to be used by end users. At the same time, the developers continue to support it and analyze the user experience.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7planning-based-on-user-experience-new-functionality-is-being-developed-and-a-plan-of-improvements-is-being-prepared-after-that-the-developer-starts-writing-code--and-the-cycle-closes&#34;&gt;7)Planning. Based on user experience, new functionality is being developed and a plan of improvements is being prepared. After that, the developer starts writing code — and the cycle closes.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;pros-and-cons-of-cicd&#34;&gt;Pros and cons of CI/CD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-minimum-time-from-the-clients-request-to-launch-into-use-the-methodology-reduces-the-time-for-launching-updates-to-several-days-in-some-cases-weeks-thanks-to-this-developers-get-the-opportunity-to-test-innovations-faster-and-implement-solutions-faster-than-competitors&#34;&gt;The minimum time from the client&amp;rsquo;s request to launch into use. The methodology reduces the time for launching updates to several days (in some cases, weeks). Thanks to this, developers get the opportunity to test innovations faster and implement solutions faster than competitors.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ability-to-check-options-operational-testing-and-many-iterations-help-the-developer-to-quickly-identify-options-that-have-no-prospects-even-at-the-initial-stages&#34;&gt;The ability to check options. Operational testing and many iterations help the developer to quickly identify options that have no prospects, even at the initial stages.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-quality-of-the-result-conducting-automated-testing-helps-to-identify-errors-and-other-problems-at-the-earliest-stages-of-development-with-the-standard-release-approach-this-is-difficult-or-impossible-to-do&#34;&gt;The quality of the result. Conducting automated testing helps to identify errors and other problems at the earliest stages of development. With the standard release approach, this is difficult or impossible to do.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;experience-requirements-in-theory-all-corporate-it-systems-can-be-transferred-to-cicd-but-in-practice-to-get-a-result-you-need-primary-experience-with-the-methodology-as-well-as-the-correct-organization-of-the-restructuring-of-all-processes&#34;&gt;Experience requirements. In theory, all corporate IT systems can be transferred to CI/CD. But in practice, to get a result, you need primary experience with the methodology, as well as the correct organization of the restructuring of all processes.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-complexity-of-ensuring-interaction-continuous-updating-and-continuous-delivery-should-be-clearly-coordinated-which-is-possible-only-after-careful-adjustment-of-interaction-between-specialists-at-all-levels&#34;&gt;The complexity of ensuring interaction. Continuous updating and continuous delivery should be clearly coordinated, which is possible only after careful adjustment of interaction between specialists at all levels.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;cicd--hype-or-necessity&#34;&gt;CI/CD — hype or necessity?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cicd-is-one-of-the-hype-software-development-methodologies-for-the-first-time-the-idea-of-its-implementation-was-announced-in-2006-and-already-in-2008-experts-expressed-the-opinion-that-its-popularity-is-associated-with-the-development-of-cloud-services-at-the-same-time-the-desire-to-use-it-to-solve-other-tasks-is-not-due-to-popularity-but-to-the-advantages-of-the-system--the-ability-to-quickly-coordinate-and-implement-updates-based-on-user-experience&#34;&gt;CI/CD is one of the hype software development methodologies. For the first time the idea of its implementation was announced in 2006, and already in 2008, experts expressed the opinion that its popularity is associated with the development of cloud services. At the same time, the desire to use it to solve other tasks is not due to popularity, but to the advantages of the system — the ability to quickly coordinate and implement updates based on user experience.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-conditions-of-fierce-competition-this-methodology-becomes-a-necessity-because-it-allows-you-to-significantly-reduce-the-time-from-code-development-to-product-release-cicd-is-suitable-for-tasks-related-to-web-development-omnichannel-solutions-e-commerce-and-other-complex-frontend-and-middleware-components-however-the-introduction-of-continuous-integration--continuous-delivery-is-not-always-justified--for-example-in-areas-with-rare-software-updates-the-methodology-will-not-justify-itself&#34;&gt;In conditions of fierce competition, this methodology becomes a necessity, because it allows you to significantly reduce the time from code development to product release. CI/CD is suitable for tasks related to web development, omnichannel solutions, e-commerce and other complex frontend and middleware components. However, the introduction of Continuous integration &amp;amp; Continuous delivery is not always justified — for example, in areas with rare software updates, the methodology will not justify itself.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;result&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cicd-is-not-just-a-methodology-but-also-a-very-good-tool-for-the-development-team-the-longer-it-is-planned-to-develop-and-maintain-a-project-the-more-useful-it-will-be-to-have-a-well-designed-cicd-all-the-resources-and-costs-of-this-tool-pay-off-at-a-distance-with-its-help-time-to-market-is-indisputably-reduced-and-the-probability-of-making-a-mistake-is-also-reduced-the-most-important-thing-is-to-keep-the-instrument-in-good-condition&#34;&gt;CI/CD is not just a methodology, but also a very good tool for the development team. The longer it is planned to develop and maintain a project, the more useful it will be to have a well-designed CI/CD. All the resources and costs of this tool pay off at a distance. With its help, time-to-market is indisputably reduced, and the probability of making a mistake is also reduced. The most important thing is to keep the instrument in good condition.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 06:36:37 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-last-week&#34;&gt;My last week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-this-week-i-made-almost-all-things-which-i-planned-i-have-done-all-the-laboratory-work-in-several-subjects-went-to-the-amusement-park-with-my-friends-read-a-new-detective-book-and-watched-an-interesting-film-called-bird-box-of-all-the-planned-things-i-could-not-only-study-english&#34;&gt;For this week i made almost all things which I planned. I have done all the laboratory work in several subjects, went to the amusement park with my friends, read a new detective book and watched an interesting film called &amp;ldquo;Bird box&amp;rdquo;. Of all the planned things, I could not only study English.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;result-of-the-week&#34;&gt;Result of the week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-my-mind-that-week-was-pretty-productive-for-me-i-didnt-have-time-to-do-only-one-planned-thing-i-think-that-situation-happened-because-i-spent-in-social-media-so-much-time-so-that-this-does-not-happen-again-i-must-keep-track-of-time-which-i-waste-in-social-media&#34;&gt;To my mind, that week was pretty productive for me. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to do only one planned thing. I think, that situation happened because I spent in social media so much time. So that this does not happen again, I must keep track of time which i waste in social media.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Wowchemy, the website builder for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wowchemy website builder for Hugo, along with its starter templates, is designed for professional creators, educators, and teams/organizations - although it can be used to create any kind of site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The template can be modified and customised to suit your needs. It&amp;rsquo;s a good platform for anyone looking to take control of their data and online identity whilst having the convenience to start off with a &lt;strong&gt;no-code solution (write in Markdown and customize with YAML parameters)&lt;/strong&gt; and having &lt;strong&gt;flexibility to later add even deeper personalization with HTML and CSS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can work with all your favourite tools and apps with hundreds of plugins and integrations to speed up your workflows, interact with your readers, and much more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-template-is-mobile-first-with-a-responsive-design-to-ensure-that-your-site-looks-stunning-on-every-device&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-started&#34;&gt;Get Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/templates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a new site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalize your site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chat with the &lt;strong&gt;Wowchemy community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐦 Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wowchemy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@GeorgeCushen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23MadeWithWowchemy&amp;amp;src=typed_query&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#MadeWithWowchemy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💡 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Request a &lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt; or report a &lt;strong&gt;bug&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⬆️ &lt;strong&gt;Updating Wowchemy?&lt;/strong&gt; View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/hugo-tutorials/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Update Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crowd-funded-open-source-software&#34;&gt;Crowd-funded open-source software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help us develop this template and software sustainably under the MIT license, we ask all individuals and businesses that use it to help support its ongoing maintenance and development via sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-click-here-to-become-a-sponsor-and-help-support-wowchemys-future-httpswowchemycomplans&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;❤️ Click here to become a sponsor and help support Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s future ❤️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a token of appreciation for sponsoring, you can &lt;strong&gt;unlock &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; awesome rewards and extra features 🦄✨&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/hugo-academic-cli&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo Academic CLI&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically import publications from BibTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out the latest &lt;strong&gt;demo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/user-stories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;view the &lt;strong&gt;showcase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of personal, project, and business sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/import/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/install-locally/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 34+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wowchemy and its templates come with &lt;strong&gt;automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Alternatively, visitors can choose their preferred mode - click the moon icon in the top right of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt; to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in &lt;code&gt;params.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Choose a stunning &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for your site. Themes are fully customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://example.com/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://owchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An example conference paper</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publication/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publication/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Create your slides in Markdown - click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button to check out the example.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code, math, and images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
